# **Nael Alismail**

nael@naelalismail.com https://github.com/maestroh https://linkedin.com/in/naelalismail

## **Summary**

Leader with over a decade of technical experience in interacting with stakeholders and development teams to deliver high quality software to meet business needs. High quality is achieved using best practices, knowledge sharing and technologies for a multidimensional approach to improvement. Known for delivering effective solutions with little information or direction. Educated and experienced in many development processes.

## Experience

### Manager of Atlanta Development & Application Architect

AppRiver

7/2008 - Present

**Atlanta Expansion** 

Entrusted with moving to Atlanta to expand the company's development department Successfully created and recruited for multiple teams from the talent pool in Atlanta

Trained and managed the remote teams

Spread company culture and kept a strong line of communication with the existing teams in the main office

#### **Departmental Leadership**

Allocated resources across teams to meet the needs of the business

Conducted performance reviews and salary discussions with engineers

Championed the implementation of Scrum

Created standard developer reviews that reflected the engineer's contribution as well as encouraged growth Created policies for public communication guidelines for use in blog posts and speaking at conferences Presented topics ranging from software development principles and best practices to technical topics

#### **Team Leadership**

Directed, designed and developed the release of multiple projects

Improved teams' speed and quality by using retrospectives to identify areas of improvement

Fostered engineer career advancement through mentoring sessions

Actively participated in design, development and sprints

Championed automated testing using technologies including Jasmine, SpecFlow and NCrunch

Championed new technologies including WebAPI and Reactive Extensions (Rx and RxJS)

#### **Web Application Development**

Built a CRM application using **LINQ**, **SQL** and **ASP.NET Web Forms** for use by sales, support and billing staff Developed partner management tools using **ASP.NET Web Forms**, **Angular**, **WCF** and **Event Sourcing** technologies Built features in an updated CRM application using **Angular**, **SignalR**, **WCF** and a service bus technology Created service management tools for use by customers

Worked closely with product management and stakeholders to define features and timelines

#### **API Development**

Designed, built and maintained service management APIs with technologies including **WebAPI**, **WCF** and **SOAP** Developed system and integration tests using **NUnit** and **SpecFlow** 

Developed unit tests using NUnit and Moq

Used **dependency injection** to decouple architecture and ease unit testing

Accessed data from SQL Server and MongoDB

Stored data for Hosted Exchange using Active Directory

Founder bopmob.com
Digital Audio Workstation 9/2014 - Present

Built a digital audio workstation using the latest web technologies

Built the client side using ReactJs, FlexBox, Web Audio API, and RxJS

Developed the backend API using Node.js and Express

Created Helm Control for build automation

Wrote client side and server side testing using Mocha, JSDom, and SimpleMock

Hosted on DigitalOcean on a Linux instance with using PM2 to manage the process

Application Developer NFP

Cobranding Application 7/2006 - 6/2008

Built a cobranding solution for insurance and securities disclaimers

Conducted interviews with stakeholders to gather requirements and understand the domain

Created an HTTP module to redirect users based on the users' state

Developed a single sign on solution

Unified data across multiple data sources using ASP.NET Web Services

Programmer Analyst Sungard

Benefits Application 6/2004 - 6/2006

Maintained and enhanced benefits web application written in ASP.NET Web Forms

Converted a web application from .NET 1.1 to .NET 2.0

Developed customer service representative application

### Education

Master of Science in Software Engineering	University of West Florida	2014
Certified ScrumMaster	Scrum Alliance	2014
Leadership Training	AppRiver Sherpa Executive Coaching Program	2013
Bachelor of Science	University of Alabama at Birmingham	2004